Personal Info

Name: Farouk Bakre

Address: Journalist Estate Phase 2, Arepo, Ogun, Nigeria.

Phone: +2348145251688

E-mail: faroukbakre@gmail.com

Website: http://www.faroukbakre.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/faroukbakre/

GitHub: https://github.com/Farbaks

Dribbble: https://dribbble.com/Farbaks

Creative software engineer with 2+ years' experience participating in the complete software development lifecycle of successfully launched web and mobile applications. In previous roles, identified and resolved bottlenecks in codebase that optimized application performance by up to 20%; refactored mobile application codebase which increased efficiency and maintainability by 50%.

Experience

Frontend Developer - February 2021 - Present

Sudo Africa

- Build a fully functional Online Banking Platform for account owners at Safe Haven Micro Finance Bank through which they can check account balance and transaction history, make transfers, view statements and update account info.
- Implement new features on Sudo Africa Dashboard for registered users to allow easy account and debit/credit card control and integration of existing Sudo APIs.

Software Engineer • December 2019 – February 2021

Serve Consulting Ltd.

- Refactored the mobile application using Ionic/Angular to optimize performance and maintainability across all platforms by 50%.
- Maintained the web application with over 5,000 daily users.
- Identified and resolve bottlenecks in codebase to optimize application performance by up to 20%.
- Created detailed, well-structured test cases and assist team members in testing.
- Diagnosed and fixed issues found on the web application during testing phases to ensure features are well optimized and free of bugs.

Software Developer - August 2018 - October 2018

New Usual Ltd.

- Developed a car repair web application, which provides hundreds of its users with car repair and towing services, using jQuery, PHP/MySQL.
- Collaborated with software development team to implement new feature developments.

Education

2014 - 2019

Bells University of Technology B.Tech.,

Computer Science.

Skills

- HTML, CSS and JavaScript, jQuery, Typescript, React, Angular, NgRx, Electron, Vue, VueX, Nuxt, Ionic, Nodejs, Nestjs, PHP, Laravel, MySQL, GraphQL, Git, Heroku.
- Experience of writing and consuming REST APIs.
- · Excellent communication skills.
- Analytical thinking and problem-solving capability.
- Fast learner.
- Creative thinker.